If
this becomes a standard, which I think
it will be and slowly is,
it actually opens up some more attack
surface because we have a little bit
more to play with.
Best part of hacking when you can just,
you know, critical thing, right?
All right, y'all. We've talked about
ThreatLocker ring-fencing a lot. We know
how it allows you to set ACLs and
policies for exactly what an application
is allowed to do in your network. But
today, I'm going to tell you how it does
that, okay? Three technologies:
mini-filter drivers, Windows Filtering
Platform, and EX version kernel
notification routines. Mini-filter
drivers are essentially a hook or
callback for um IO requests, okay? So,
when you're trying to write or read from
a file, you can create a hook with those
and approve or deny based off of the
ThreatLocker ACL. Windows Filtering
Platform, similar situation, but for
connect bind uh requests, right? You can
say, "Okay, hey, is this process allowed
to talk to port 443 over there on the
internet? Yes or no?" Approve or deny.
Lastly, you've got EX version kernel
notification routines. The EX version's
important because uh it allows you to
approve or deny versus just getting a
notification from the kernel.
Um and this is specific for um hooking
various native API calls like NT create
user process, which is what you would
use to like spin up powershell.exe or
something like that, okay? So, those
three are very useful to ThreatLocker's
ring-fencing core technology. Hope you
enjoyed learning how this is
implemented. Check out ThreatLocker if
you think you would benefit from
something like that. All right, let's go
back to the show.
Hey, what's up, guys? It's Brandon, and
this week in Bug Bounty is short, but it
is very good news for some of you
hackers out there, and it's from
integrity. Now, integrity is
collaborating with PortSwigger.
And
what this means is if you get a certain
amount of reputation points per quarter,
you'll be getting a free 6-month Burp
license. Now, in order to be valid for
this,
you need to achieve 400 or more valid
reputation in a single quarter, and then
you get a free 6-month Burp license.
Now, I'm not too sure how long it takes
for the license to come through, but you
will be eligible for a license. So,
if you haven't got a paid-for proxy yet,
um if Burp Suite is your go-to or if you
want a community edition, this one might
be for you, and it's a very good way
to get a paid-for license. So, check
that out if you are in need of a Burp
Suite license. As I said, 400
reputation.
And looking at the score breakdown on
integrity, um exceptional's 50 points,
critical's 40 points, high's 25, medium
20, low five points. So, just to give
you a bit of an idea of what you'll have
to be hunting for in terms of quantity.
So, if you need a license, definitely
check that out. But yeah, that's it for
this week, guys. Have fun.
Hey guys, it's me, Brandon Greatme, back
with a solo episode today.
It's been a while since I've last been
on.
Um
I can attribute that to LHE season. It's
been very busy. I've had mm
three back-to-back events now for
what feels like 2 years instead of 2
months, so it's been very busy. And now,
Reza and and Ryan Rader are out on their
LHE, so
it's just going to be me today. Now,
this episode is being driven from a part
of the scope that I focused on in one of
these live events.
Um and I realized when I started digging
into our season, looking at some of this
functionality, um,
how impactful it could be on the rest of
our scope and how we look at things
going forward in the OAuth spec and the
OAuth implementation.
Now, there's a few upcoming changes
happening, um,
with regards to the OAuth 2.1 standard,
and I'm just going to share my screen
real quick for people watching.
Now,
the OAuth 2.1 standard, some, um,
providers have already started
implementing this,
um, for agent to agent stuff, but we'll
get on to that shortly. But, the OAuth
2.1 standard states that, uh, PKCE is
mandatory.
Um, the implicit flow has been removed.
The client credentials, sorry, not
client credentials, the password
credentials flow is getting removed. Um,
redirect URI matching has to be exact
string only, instead of any wildcards or
some of the, um,
loose path matching that it does now
in some frameworks. Um, bearer tokens
are no longer allowed to be in URIs, um,
either. So, that massively changes the
attack surface from what we're used to.
So, just to summarize, servers must
reject requests that miss the code
challenge, uh, parameter. Implicit and
password credentials flows are are going
to die out. Uh, redirect URIs require
exact string matching.
Bear, um,
no more access tokens in URIs, and
this is quite interesting because it
brings quite a significant change to
what we're used to. So, the new proposed
changes, which some frameworks are
already implementing, is that the
authorization header is preferred
for transmitting the token
instead of the URI.
And also, if this header can't be
utilized for whatever reason, it can be
transmitted as forming coded
within a request body.
So,
what led me to this is on one of the
targets, I can't say
unfortunately, but there was some
interesting functionality around
the MCP and agent agent authentication
and how that's handled as well. Now,
this actually brings an entirely new
threat model
to OAuth frameworks as a whole
if they start implementing and becoming
2.1 spec compliant and even if their
ecosystem starts to change as well. And
that is because of the MCP authorization
spec.
Now,
I'm just going to reshare my screen
here.
Now,
the MCP authorization spec, I've got a
diagram up for people that aren't
listening, builds on top of OAuth 2.1.
That then uses and builds on top of RFC
8414 and RFC 7591, which is server data
server metadata discovery and dynamic
client registration. And that then
builds the MCP authorization spec
um
as a whole.
So, the traditional flow that we used to
with the dynamic client registration
flow is we send the HTTP post request to
the register endpoint contain redirect
URI, grant type, logo, and client name,
and then the authorization server
returns client ID, client secret, and
issue that. Now, we're very much used to
that traditional threat model when you
introduce
the logo URIs for SSRF and things like
that.
Um but now with the new introduced
client identity metadata document, that
changes a little bit. So, the flow here
is
the
agent
sends a request to the authorization
server
containing a client manifest URI, a
scope, and response type.
That authorization server
takes that and stores it in the metadata
verification service or verifies it
there as well.
And it's passing and validating the
redirect URI, uh the JWKS URI, logo URI,
and so on.
And then that metadata verification
service
sends that back to the authorization
server.
Um
yes, no, whatever. Provides a consent
and login screen, and then passes that
off code back to the to the AI agent.
Now, this is interesting because the
threat model changes here a little bit
because I mean, the authorization server
and the metadata verification service
can be on the same host.
But,
we're now passing a client manifest URI
to both of these services where it has
to be validated. So,
the most logical thing to go after when
we're looking at this new implementation
is SSRF. Now, SSRF on the metadata
verification service is very much still
going to be present because there's
either going to be the authorization
server itself handles that or the
external identity verification service
handles that. And by the very nature of
it, they have to request the client
manifest URI and validate that
themselves. So, when we start looking at
how that validation occurs, which is
some of the things I was doing in one of
these targets in the live event,
is trying to understand, okay, when this
flow happens, first we understand what
is the user user agent that's making
this flow.
Second of all, off the back of that,
does the
service that's handling the redirect and
actually hand handling the request of
that document, does it handle different
response codes?
How does it handle those different
response codes? Does it handle different
30X response codes differently? Are
there any specific quirks on that
specific user agent if we have access to
that? Um
a long shot, but if does it handle
JavaScript processing as well if it's
maybe a headless browser that's doing
that.
Um and going down those very traditional
SSRF attack vectors.
And it's quite nice because there's two
different spots where this might
potentially occur as well with this new
client identity metadata document
registration because you have the first
request to the client manifest
and then inside the client manifest as
well, you can nest a whole range of URIs
as well which may or may not be
supported depending on the framework. So
there's two different places where this
can really come up and uh
and and increase that attack surface.
Now,
the other thing as well with this is
because the client must fetch the client
JSON document um
and must enforce that all redirect URIs
in the document belong to the same
domain.
We start to get into the standard how is
the domain validation made. So
say for example, if the service isn't
validating that the domain you're
passing as a redirect URI
um doesn't match your actual own domain,
you might be able to set a redirect for
example to attacker.com or
victim.com/callback.
Um it might accept that weak domain
check and you might be able to use that
as a primitive to leak to an external
domain as well. And the other thing that
I just wanted to touch upon as well that
I did touch upon is
the URIs
in the CIMD flow, which you can pass in
inside the client.json. I just wanted to
to clarify this. It's the logo URI and
the JWKS URI. So, test case, in your
client.json, you nest the logo URI as
the
um a target, say for example, internal,
whatever it might be, metadata endpoint,
or internal host.
You set that in there.
If the tool server fetches the logo URI
blindly and maybe displays the logo in
the UI, or gives an error on that, then
you've got a CSRF there as well. And the
other thing as well which I was thinking
about when I was starting to threat
model this service is, since the CIMD
is a static document, the um
authorization server might start to
cache some of these requests.
So, for example,
if it's validating the client.json and
it caches the results,
that
gives a whole leeway there for your
traditional cache deception and and all
those types of attack vectors as well.
So, overall, I'm just going to share the
client identity metadata document again.
So, overall,
even though the dynamic registration is
going to be slowly phased out
over time,
if
this becomes a standard, which I think
it will be and slowly is,
it actually opens up some more attack
surface because we have a little bit
more to play with in this flow as well,
and there's more things to verify. So,
it isn't all bad. So, that's the second
change I thought that was quite
interesting when I started to deep dive
and look at some of these documents off
the back of the target. Okay, so on to
the next one and that is the token
exchange RFC 8693.
So, right now
agent authentication is in a is in a
good spot, but agent authorization not
so much. I'm just going to share my
screen.
Now,
right now there's a lot of token
pass-throughs everywhere, which is if
you hack AI of or if you're looking at
these multi-agent workflows on the on
the blue team side, you'll know that
this is a problem where
token pass-through right now, so the
user token has all the scopes, which
then get passed agent A. Agent A needs
to spin up agent B um and agent C in the
agentic workflow.
And delegate all these different tasks
over um and right now all these agents
inherit the same token and the same
scope. Now, the token exchange RFC 8693
um gives a mean for
agent-to-agent communication
to reduce the scope on each hop. So, say
for example, your user token the scope
is full as you'd expect.
You give that to agent A and the scope
you only want to give agent A because it
handles very specific task is just uh
calendar read for example.
Now, when agent A invokes um agent B for
example, um
it can do that on the next hop and just
give it uh
a reduced scope for that hop. So, you
get from this situation where
you have a full scopes token being
passed from every single agent and it
just gets passed downstream. If you look
at any of this traffic, it will simply
just have you'll have a authorization
header with that token and each agent
just appends it on and tags it on and
sends it to the to the next call. Um now
this addresses that where you can
reduce the scope for each hop in that
agentic workflow on agent-to-agent
communications. So,
that's pretty nice and to be honest,
if you're in any AI circle, that's been
spoken about quite a while now where
authorization is just a mess. If you
look at any targets,
I think one of the most common bugs
is around confused deputy attacks and
just agentic services or chatbots, for
example, just having almost god might to
everything. So, this,
although slightly different, aims to
address some of that over-privileged
creep uh
over-privileged scope creep that would
keeps cropping up all over the show.
So, that would be quite nice when it's
implemented. Well, not nice for us, but
something to look out for, at least.
Okay, some other things before moving on
I just wanted to mention on the token
exchange as well is that this is already
cropping up in a few targets. The one
that I'm aware of
um is Auth0. The token vault utilizes
this architecture
uh for enabling the um
AI agent integrations.
And the other thing as well, um
token pass-through uh
when you directly forward user
credentials as a primary driver for
confused deputy exploits.
Now, I know in one of the live events at
people had just been in Japan,
um there were a lot of these
confused deputy-based attack vectors
happening on this target.
So, definitely something to keep an eye
out for.
Okay, so
in 2.0, PKCE is now required by default
instead of being optional. And PKCE,
Proof Key for Code Exchange, is used to
prevent authorization code interception
essentially. And you would have probably
seen it on requests through the code
challenge parameter. Now,
it's interesting because in a
normal PKCE flow,
the client will send its code challenge,
the server stores that code challenge,
the client then sends a code verifier,
and then that's then verified, and if
they match, you get the token issued.
With a downgrade attack, um
the code challenge is stripped from the
the request or set to a a default value.
If the server accepts the request
without it,
that then facilitates the authorization
codes to be stolen and then exchanged
without no verifier needed.
Um
So, the main vector here,
when this is implemented by default on
frameworks that are 2.1 compliant, um or
are migrating to be 2.1 compliant, is
looking around the PKCE downgrade
attacks. Now, I do have a couple of CVEs
that I found
off the back of this research as well,
which uh
highlight this quite nicely. One of the
big ones that I saw which went under my
radar initially was by Zero Path. And
essentially, it was in
Django OAuth, which is quite a big
library. And the implementation flaw was
in the fact that it utilized the
preferred username from the OAuth
response as the account UID.
When you are looking at these
frameworks, it's important to understand
that what claims should be writeable
and what claims should be used as your
source of truth because there are claims
that are mutable or writable by users
themselves. And in this case, preferred
username was actually actually a mutable
claim
on certain providers. So, what this
allows to do is an attacker, for
example, can set their preferred
username themselves. They just set that
to admin or victim.com and they can get
account takeover on that. I'm just going
to show my screen on this research cuz
it does deserve a shout out.
Now,
as I said by ZeroPath and it was seven
vulnerabilities in Django OAuth which
let them achieve account impersonation.
Now, it is a pretty big library, as I
said, with What's that? 2 million
monthly downloads
and
four major vulnerabilities
were identified in the library with the
different providers
that it integrates with is that Octa
identifiers are mutable, NetIQ
identifiers are also mutable. Tokens for
deactivated users could be
refreshed indefinitely. Now,
in these live events, the reason why I
wanted to share this research is because
these are the exact things I was looking
for in some of these implementations as
well.
Um
and that is if a user gets deactivated
or if the state of that user account
gets changed in some way
to a state where the user shouldn't be
able to access something, how is that
how is that user's token handled and how
is the user's refresh token handled as
well?
Um can you just use a refresh token to
still get the same claims
and same attributes as it was when it
was first issued or is the refresh token
also updated on the server side as well.
Now,
the biggest vulnerabilities from this
write-up are obviously the mutable
attributes being used for certain
providers. So,
as it says here, uh the function uses
the OAuth response field preferred
username as the account UID. Many OAuth
and OIDC providers expose a stable sub
subject claim and an optimal user-facing
field like preferred username.
Preferred username is often mutable and
not globally unique.
Now, that's important here because
when an application or a library is
identifying its users
um through a claim, that claim has to be
immutable because otherwise a user can
just create their own claim or overwrite
an existing claim and use it as a source
of truth. Now, this is actually also
can be quite an interesting primitive
for privilege escalation bugs.
If you see uh a permission set or
something else as a claim, which one you
can overwrite and two is being used as a
source of source of truth
for something in the application,
definitely try and overwrite that
because it can lead to some really
interesting bugs. So,
just keep track of that as well.
Uh I think this uh
blog write-up was a RuneScape player as
well if you get the Zezima Sazama
reference, however you say it.
Um but yeah, quite a good blog post. Um
it contains code snippets as well, so
definitely go and check that one out by
0Auth, but those are the two
points I wanted to mention.
Now, the other one I wanted to mention
is touches upon the point that we just
talked about around the
new RFCs and where some of this
ambiguity is going to start coming in on
implementation flaws. And that one is a
PKCE
uh bypass on Cloudflare workers. Now,
this one took a little bit of digging
in. I've got the
GitHub advisory shared on screen right
now, but essentially the bug was in the
handle token request. It accepted a code
verifier even if the initial
authorization request admitted the code
challenge. So, by stripping the code
challenge, you could essentially exploit
the lack of enforcement and steal the
off code in exchange of a a valid
verifier.
Now, this one affected all Cloudflare
workers as well.
And you can see here that the MCP
specification requires OAuth 2.0 stated
in that advisory as well. So,
yeah, quite a interesting one off the
back of some of the
new implementation.
Okay. So, the next one is again by Zero
Path and it is
Let me share my screen. CV 2025-5476
and it is a authentication bypass on
OAuth 2 proxy, which is quite a big and
popular
gateway used for Kubernetes and cloud
environments and essentially
there's a feature in this framework that
allows you to specify regex patterns for
paths that should bypass authentication
completely.
So, say if you have a specific path that
you needed to be publicly accessible and
you didn't want it wrapped or sat behind
the proxy, you would just go, "Okay,
here's a regex for that path." And have
at it and it'll be publicly accessible.
Now, there's an implementation flaw
in the fact that the regex actually
matched against the entire request URI.
Now, that's interesting because if you
match against the entire request URI,
you have query parameters in there as as
And that meant that
you could essentially match a request
by doing something like
uh  endpoint  endpoint 100
access.
Um,
question mark parameter equals and then
the rejects which is used to to skip
that path.
And because the parameter is also
matched on that rejects, this lead to a
complete off bypass uh for those
specific endpoints. And what that would
allow an attacker to do is actually get
authentication being skipped for
requests and endpoints that should have
been protected simply by matching that
uh bypass rejects
in the as a request parameter in the URI
instead of actually being the URI
itself. So,
quite a quite an interesting CVE. Um,
but yeah, this was by Zero Point CVE
54576 on OAuth 2 proxy.
Now, the last one that did make me laugh
which I'll share shortly,
um,
is
from Pentester Lab CV from this year,
quite fresh.
And I didn't know
that Harbor existed as a language. I
didn't even know what Harbor was until I
found this out, but still the bug's
pretty funny. Um,
anyway, the TLDR here is that the
classic none algorithm algorithm is
supported. Um, and in this one,
it was actually any unknown algorithm uh
gets that bypass. So,
quite funny as you can set the algorithm
to banana or
zzz or whatever it might be. Um, it gets
passed to the framework or library or
you pass in none and uh
it just basically fails open and
bypasses signature verification
altogether. So, that was CVE 2026-23993
by Pentester Labs, so
check that one out as well.
Okay, so
just to wrap up for everyone. It's a bit
of a shorter episode today, but just
cover some really cool changes and
interesting things that's going to start
creeping in
to things we're looking at. So,
the core OAuth 2.1 protocol PKCE is
mandatory. Servers must reject requests
that don't contain the code challenge.
Implicit flow and password credentials
are dead. They're going to be phased
out.
Redirect URIs now require exact string
matching instead of
wildcard matching that sometimes we used
to.
Bearer tokens are prohibited in URIs.
Um
PKCE downgrade attacks are going to be
quite
fruitful.
And some other things as well around
where some of these bugs might come up
is look for the transition gaps when
frameworks are going from 2.0 to 2.1 and
trying to
be cross-compatible and make sure all
their clients
um are still in a working state is that
there's going to be a lot of
compatibility shims where a lot of
bugs show up in. So, if you see a target
claiming OAuth 2.1 compliance, check out
the downgrade attacks for examples. Um
Now, the second takeaway is the uh CIMD
SSRF for the new way for the client
metadata to to register.
Now,
that's an SSRF goldmine. So, if you see
that implemented or see support for it,
definitely check it out. Um and passing
that metadata document and nest that
with your own
redirect URIs or targets, whatever you
want to do, as well.
Now, the third point is authentication
is in a fairly strong spot, but
delegation and authorization
is still in a pretty bad spot and
there's a lot of bugs there. So, look
for token pass-through. If an agent is
calling a tool,
um try and
disclose how how it calls that tool.
Look at the traffic if you can.
Um understand the request structure and
see if the tool includes a full
privilege token rather than a small
scopes token just for that specific
action.
So, that's the takeaways for this week,
guys. I think OAuth 2.1 is going to be
quite interesting when we start seeing
a lot of the frameworks and libraries
that we interact with start implementing
it and trying to get a lot of these
changes cross-compatible
um and ensuring that clients are
supported.
But, that is it for this week. I think
me and Justin will be covering some of
the fun we had in the recent event in an
upcoming episode, so look out for that.
But, yeah, that's it for this week,
guys. Peace.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching till the end, y'all. If you
want more Critical Thinking content uh
or if you want to support the show, head
over to ctbb.show/discord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great high-level hacking
discussion happening there on top of the
master classes, hackathons, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild
if you're a full-time hunter. It's a
great time, trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.